Erika Huszar

Location: London | Telephone: 07753182312 | Nationality: British | Email: Erikahuszar8@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/huszarerika | CodePen Profile: https://codepen.io/erika888

Portfolio: https://erikahuszar.github.io/#hero | GitHub: https://github.com/ErikaHuszar

Reference available upon request

Profile

I enjoy the challenges of the IT Profession with an enthusiastic, professional approach to my work, with total commitment and reliability. My curiosity about how computers are used in the world and how people are using those technologies can benefit them, has made me very interested about how I can create something that can impact other people's lives. Currently, I am studying Computer Science at the University of Westminster and looking for an opportunity in the field of front-end development at a dynamic organisation. With an experience of more than 10 years as a Nail Technician working with some of the most high profile and demanding clients in the world, I decided to change my career path into a more technical and challenging route. In this new field, the skills I obtained helped me to become a highly skilled and knowledgeable computer science student with extensive knowledge of programming and computer applications.

Achievements

Python 3 SoloLearn:

Issued March 2019, No Expiration Date

https://www.sololearn.com/Certificate/1073-9280343/pdf/

Front end Libraries: (FreecodeCamp)

Issued Jan 2019, No Expiration Date

https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/erikahuszar/front-end-libraries

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures: (FreecodeCamp)

Issued Jan 2019, No Expiration Date

https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/erikahuszar/javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures

Education

Computer Science BSc (September 2019 – Present)

University of Westminster (First year: First Class Honours)

During my first year of university, I have learnt the fundamentals of computer systems and applying the theory into real-world applications using industrial tools such as SQL and PHP and technology platforms like GitHub to collaborate with team members throughout the course. Learning to program in various native and web languages like HTML, CSS, JavaScript allowed me to dive into group projects and deliver a fully functional tourist website as well as using technical skills such as planning flowcharts and UML diagram to have the ability creating my first individual command-line application for a train ticket/seat reservation system using Java and also creating a student progression prediction program using python.

Additionally, transferring a lot of my soft skills from my previous experience such as team working with my colleagues and communication to my clients, given me the confidence to apply these skills to organise meetings and minutes with my group when considering everyone's schedule. I coordinated the dates of the meetings to prevent conflicting schedules, assigned the tasks for everyone within the group, and organised a communicative structure of collaboration. Overall group collaboration allowed me to improve my soft skills even more that are transferable in the areas of commercial awareness, leadership and organisation.

Using all of the above skills I have learnt in my first year, it has helped me to build out a route within computer science that suits my interests and drives my passion forward.

Computing Foundation September 2018 – May – 2019

London South Bank University

Mathematics 1 – Result: 86% (1st), Mathematics 2 – Result: 91% (1st), Computer Applications – Result: 91% (1st), Computer Technology – Result: 77% (1st), Project– Result: 71% (1st), Software Development – Result: 87% (1st), Technical Communication– Result: 71% (1st).

Projects

Lego Database

We had a client that provided young students with the opportunity to study computer science, through a more creative way where they used Lego pieces to make robots and using python to program these robots. Our client had a problem in the maintenance of the Lego pieces, as it was hard to keep track of it all and provide the correct pieces for the correct model, and therefore we have been asked by our client to develop such a database which helps to solve this issue. I undertook a real-world project with a group of 4.

- I was the group leader and managed meetings twice every week, made a group contribution page on 'Trello' which is a way for anyone to visually see what we have done and contribute to how we can make it better.
- I Learnt how to work with a client in a real business environment
- On successful completion of the project, our client offered us a job to teach young students about programming.

Stem Ambassador

Being elected to help inspire the next generation of children to engage them into "STEM activities". My job was to Prepare these students for all 4 areas (Science, Technology, Engineering, Maths).

- I Helped children Learn how to use Python.
- Learning to solve problems and work with younger people.

Code Culture

Volunteering for giving seminars for students to help them understand more about the uses of the computer science field.

- Teaching HTML, CSS, Javascript, Github and design for students
- Developing a skill to share resources with others and collaborate as a team.
- learnt to push demotivated students and think of new innovative ways to present new theories in more creative and interesting ways.

Experience

Tech Lead | Developing and Planning, ENVAL-TECH [STARTUP], Southwark, London, United Kingdom

February 2020 - May 2020

- Project planning and to provide a suitable solution using collaborative tools towards the E-Learning centre.
- Data Migration using SQL to create Enval-Tech a fully functional login/register system.
- Addressing ethical issues and aiming to release the platform, online.

I.T Ambassador (Lego Project) London South Bank University 103 Borough Rd, London SE1 0AA

May 2019 - September 2019

- Teaching students ethical Hacking, Python programming, and Robotics
- Content creation of Robotics Coding classes
- Website Maintenance
- I have learnt that giving a good lecture requires you to cultivate skills I've not used before For example, avoiding monotonous tone is very important to keep them interested in what you're talking about.
- Database Maintenance

Harrods, Knightsbridge SW1X 7XL, London (Senior Nail Technician)

April 2015 – April 2019

- Always maintaining a friendly manner and remain calm and positive when addressing customer grievances and complaints about both VIP clients and the public alike.
- Quickly achieved outstanding results under high pressure
- In order to adapt to an ever-changing and demanding environment like the Harrods shop floor, I
 have learnt to become proficient in prioritising various tasks without losing any quality of
 service.

BLISS SPA Sloane ave, SW3 3DD Kensington, London (United Kingdom) (Nail Technician)

April 2009 – March 2015

- I took my full interest in my client's conversation, which allowed me to form a stronger relationship with the client that helped the company obtain loyal clients.
- As a bliss spa employee, I was always a friendly and outgoing technician and I loved to provide an enjoyable and unforgettable experience for any client.

RETAIL FAMILY BUSINESS Hungary (Business Owner)

1998-2008

- Managed all deliveries, supplies and controlled the stocks in 5 branches.
- Built a successful team of over 20 retail professionals who delivered their KPIs and drove an increased revenue to the business.